Timothy Chow

Phone: 778 938 9907 Email: tmc21@sfu.ca Portfolio: Coming Soon

ABOUT

I'm a visual UX designer from Vancouver, BC In my work, I aim to create holistic experiences where I focus on making things meaningful. I believe that looking deeper into details matter because who you are designing for matters.

Currently, I am in my third year studying interaction design at Simon Fraser University.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

anec + dote

February 2018

Designed the front end an e-commerce platform that offers a selection of printed literature.

Utilized atomic design methodology to work in a detailed manner to develop the responsiveness of anec + dote.

COMPETENCIES

DESIGN TECHNICAL

User experience Adobe CC Interface design Sketch Interaction design Principle Visual design Flinto Illustration SketchUp HTML, CSS Strategy

Personas JavaScript

Heuristics Journey frameworks

User testing Copywriting

Generative research

Yelp: Feature Design

January 2018

Designed a compare feature for Yelp's existing platform that allows people to compare results rather than loading themselves with information.

Conducted primary, secondary, and evaluative research on

Yelp's interface and interactions

Developed prototypes and wireframes to tackle problems

within the interface

RESEARCH **WORKING ON**

photogra-VR

Designed and prototyped a virtual reality headset for

travelling photographers.

November - December 2017 Conducted primary and secondary research on materiality

and product interactions.

EDUCATION

SIMON FRASER UNIVERSITY

MAJOR

Fall 2015 - Present

· Pursuing a Bachelor of Arts in Interactive Arts and Technology with a concentration in design.

Spring 2018 - Present MINOR

· Pursuing a minor in Print and Digital Publishing.

INDUSTRY CONNECT

GRAPHICS AND MEDIA ARTS

2015

· Stepping stone in my career where I learned technical skills prior to enrolling into SFU.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Assistant Production Editor

The Peak Publications, part-time Fall 2017 - Present

Tasked with laying out and designing pages within the paper, ensuring a high quality product.

Collaborated with section editors in order to convey the written piece visually.

Graphic Designer

Emerging Generations, volunteer Fall 2017 - Present

Worked with existing branding to produce name tags and event banners for Facebook and their website.

Collaborated with the parties involved so that the materials reflect its branding and event information.

RECOGNITION

ENTREPRENEURSHIP AND INNOVATION

Placed 1st in an academic entrepreneurship and innovation class with a proposal to mend the relationship between transit and people with non-visible disabilities.

Audio Technician

Emerging Generations, volunteer 2013 - 2016

Prepared sound equipment and operated the sound board in order to achieve a sound mix that would vitalize the spirits of guests.

Collaborated with band in order to make them feel comfortable with how they sound.